YUSUF YUSUF AROWOSAYE



- +2348161196688
- yarowosaye@gmail.
- Shooto /12
 Ilorin ,Nigeria

ABOUT ME

Skilled recent graduate with a Bachelor of science in Chemical Engineering with experience operating and analyzing process model. Developed an understanding in following areas: Unit Operations! Transport Phenomena! Chemical Reactions Engineering! Process Dynamics & Control! Thermodynamics! Petroleum Technology! Calculus and Analytical Calculations! Materials Science! Technical Reports Writing! Health, Safety & Environment! Business & Project management.

EXPERIENCE

National Youth Service Corps: Goldtest College Ilorin | 2018 - 2019

Class Teacher

Kwara State Water Works (Asa-Dam) | April 2016 - October 2016

Process Engineer Trainee

Responsible for water treatment, laboratory test on water qualities and distribution of treated water to final consumers.

Faculty Of Engineering Ahmadu Bello University |

Students Work Experience Program

EDUCATION

Duke University | September 2019 - October 2019

Oil & Gas industry operations and market

Environment And Safety Management Institute | September 2018 - December 2018

Professional Diploma In Health, Safety And Environment

Ahmadu Bello University | 2012 - 2017

B. Eng Chemical Engineering

Socrates College Ilorin | 2004 - 2010

Senior Secondary Certificate Examination

Model Nursery And Primary School College Of Education Ilorin. | 1998 - 2004

Primary School Leaving Certicate

PROJECTS

Research Project, Ahmadu Bello University | 2016 - 2017(11 months)

Effect Of Temperature On Oil Based Drilling Fluid Formulated From Jatropha Curcus Seed oil With Localized Sourced Bentonite.

Design Project, Ahmadu Bello University | 2016 - 2017 (11 months)

Design Of 1500tons Per Annum Alum Plant Study

Study in to Alum production including plant layout, feasibility study and economic analysis, technical specifications, modeling of problems, reports writing and presentation of work.

Kwara State Water Works (Asa-Dam) | April 2016 - September 2016

Evaluation Of Performance Of Filters By Comparison With W.H.O Standards For Water Treatment. A Case Study Of Asa-Dam Plant Kwara State Water Works.

Other Info

Skills

- > Initiative, good interpersonal relationship
- > chemical Engineering operations
- > production management
- > Teaching skills (ability to impact knowledge)
- > Digital marketing skills
- > Organization and time management skills
- > A Strong verbal communication skills
- > A broad knowledge on a variety of chemical Engineering software such as AutoCAd, MATLAB, Hysis+, Microsoft office, open office.
- > Digital Marketing skills
- > Leadership experience

Interest

Reading, Research and Traveling.

References

Languages

Yoruba, English and Hausa

Others

Training / Certification

- > Fundamentals of Digital Marketing.
- > Introduction to Sustainable Development in Business.
- > Jobberman Soft skills Training.
- > Spillage Response Awareness Training.
- > COSHH Awareness.
- > COSHH and Working in Confined Spaces.
- > Health and Safety Induction.
- > Personal Protective Equipment Awareness Course.
- > Let's Break the chain of Covid-19 Infection.

Career Objective

To work in diverse and challenging organizations that will effectively utilize my skills, experience, knowledge,

Prof. Ibrahim Arowosaye Yusuf Senior Lecturer Department of public law, faculty of law University of Ilorin, P. M. B 1515, Ilorin. Email. Ibrahimyusuff@gmail.com Tel. 08132475256

Dr. Sabiu Bilal
Senior Lecturer
Department of chemical Engineering
Ahamadu Bello University, Zaria
Email. Billasabiu@gmail.com
Tel. 08033037352

Ibrahim Duro Gold, Esq HOD, Litigation Director Legal process and Archives Supreme Court of Nigeria Email. Idgold259@gmail.com Tel. 08065707587 talent and create opportunity for growth through hard work, professionalism and high ethical standard.